Some urban legends are real.
The Shortcut is a mystery, horror, thriller film directed by Nicholaus Goossen.
When Derek moves to a new town and discovers a shortcut through the woods to his high school, he learns about a
crazy old man who lives near its path: Legend has it that he abducted a group of teenagers years ago.
Ignoring the warning, Derek and his friends set out to uncover
the dark secret that's buried deep in the woods.
But will they survive to tell it?
Derek, played by Drew Seeley.
Lisa, played by Shannon Woodward.
Mark, played by Dave Franco.
Christy, played by Katrina Bowden.
Old Man / Ivor, played by Raymond J. Barry.
Mr. Hartley, played by Kent Allen.
The Shortcut is a 2009 American horror film directed by Nicholaus Goossen.
The film stars Andrew Seeley, Shannon Woodward, Dave Franco, and Katrina Bowden.
The plot centers on two brothers who discover a rarely
used shortcut and learn its dark secret.
Dan Hannon and Scott Sandler developed the screenplay in 2008 for Scary Madison Productions, the newly formed horror division of Happy Madison
Productions, the production company of Sandler's brother Adam, and Leomax Entertainment, who financed and co-produced the film.
Released in North America by Indigomotion, a division of Leomax, on September 29,
2009, the film received mixed reviews and was a commercial failure.
It ended up being the only film under the Scary Madison label, as
it was retired in response to the film's failure.
The film was released on DVD and Blu-Ray in North
America by Anchor Bay Entertainment.
The film explores themes of high school, woods, urban legend.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.